Philip Henry Sheridan Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Philip Henry Sheridan Papers 1853-1896 (bulk 1862-1887)
MSS39768
Sheridan, Philip Henry, 1831-1888
18,000 items
120 containers plus 1 oversize
46.4 linear feet
104 microfilm reels
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Army officer. Correspondence, letterbooks, telegrams, writings, reports, orders, financial records, scrapbooks, and other papers relating primarily to the Civil War, Reconstruction, Mexican border disputes, Indian wars, and Sheridan's service as commanding general of the army.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Bonsal, Rebecca M.; Forsyth, George A.--Correspondence.; Forsyth, James W. (James William), 1836-1906--Correspondence.; Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885--Correspondence.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865--Correspondence.; Page, Henry, active 1863-1865.; Sheridan, Michael V. (Michael Vincent), 1840-1918--Correspondence.; Sheridan, Philip Henry, 1831-1888.; Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891--Correspondence.; Warren, G. K. (Gouverneur Kemble), 1830-1882.
Subjects
Courts-martial and courts of inquiry.; Indians of North America--Government relations.; Indians of North America--Wars--Montana.; Indians of North America--Wars.; Piegan Indians--Wars--Montana.; Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877); Shenandoah Valley Campaign, 1864 (August-November); Shenandoah Valley Campaign, 1864 (May-August)
Places
Appomattox (Va.)--History.; Asia--Description and travel.; Bighorn Mountains (Wyo. and Mont.)--Discovery and exploration.; Boonville (Mo.)--History.; Chickamauga (Ga.)--History.; Europe--Description and travel.; Georgia--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Kentucky--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Mexico--Boundaries--United States.; Missionary Ridge (Tenn.)--History.; Mississippi--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Missouri--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Murfreesboro (Tenn).--History.; Perryville (Ky.)--History.; Ripley (Miss.)--History.; Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Tennessee--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Tullahoma (Tenn.)--History.; United States--Boundaries--Mexico.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Cavalry operations.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Virginia--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Winchester, 3rd Battle of, Winchester, Va., 1864.; Wyoming--Discovery and exploration.; Yellowstone River--Discovery and exploration.
Titles
Philip Henry Sheridan Papers at the Library of Congress
Occupations
Army officers.
Provenance
The papers of Philip Henry Sheridan, army officer, were deposited in the Library of Congress in 1931-1932 by his widow, Irene Rucker Sheridan. In 1948, heirs to his estate converted the deposit to a gift. The collection was augmented by a transfer of items from the papers of Sheridan's secretary, Daniel O. Drennan, which were donated in 1946 by Mrs. Charles H. Kneessi.
Additional Guides
In 1962, the Library published Philip H. Sheridan, A Register of His Papers in the Library of Congress. The register was amended when the papers were microfilmed in 1985.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Philip Henry Sheridan are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Microfilm
A microfilm edition of these papers is available on 104 reels. Consult reference staff in the Manuscript Division concerning availability for purchase or interlibrary loan. To promote preservation of the originals, researchers are required to consult the microfilm edition as available.
Online Content
The papers of Philip Henry Sheridan are available on the Library of Congress Web site at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/collmss.ms000038.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1831, Mar. 6 Born, Albany, N.Y.
1853 Graduated, U.S. Military Academy, West Point, N.Y.
1854 1855 Frontier duty at Fort Duncan, La Pena, and Turkey Creek, Tex.
1855 1861 Frontier duty in the Oregon and Washington territories
1861 1862 Chief quartermaster and chief commissary of the Army of the Southwest
1862 Promoted to colonel, U.S. Volunteers Commanded Second Michigan Cavalry, Volunteers Commanded Second Brigade, Cavalry Division, Army of the Mississippi Promoted to brigadier general, U.S. Volunteers Commanded Eleventh Division, Third Corps, Army of the Ohio Commanded Third Division, Right Wing, Fourteenth Army Corps Promoted to major general, U.S. Volunteers
1863 Commanded Third Division, Twentieth Army Corps, Army of the Cumberland
1863 1864 Commanded Second Division, Fourth Army Corps
1864 Commanded Cavalry Corps, Army of the Potomac Promoted to brigadier general, U.S. Army
1865 Commanded Army of the Shenandoah Commanded Middle Military Division Promoted to major general, U.S. Army Commanded all U.S. forces west of the Mississippi River
1865 1866 Commanded Military Division of the Gulf
1866 1867 Commanded Department of the Gulf
1867 Commanded Fifth Military District
1867 1869 Commanded Department of the Missouri
1869 1878 Commanded Military Division of the Missouri
1869 Promoted to lieutenant general, U.S. Army
1870 Inspected military posts in northern Utah and Montana
1870 1871 United States official observer of the Franco-Prussian War
1875 Married Irene Rucker
1877 Led Yellowstone expedition
1878 1883 Commanded Western and Southwestern Military Division
1883 Escorted Chester A. Arthur, Robert Todd Lincoln, and others on an expedition through Yellowstone Park
1883 1888 Commanding general, U.S. Army, succeeding William T. Sherman
1888 Published Personal Memoirs of P. H. Sheridan. New York: C. L. Webster. 2 vols. Promoted to general, U.S. Army
1888, Aug. 5 Died, Nonquit, Mass.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Philip Henry Sheridan (1831-1888) span the years 1853 to 1896, with the bulk of the material originating between 1862 and 1887. The collection includes correspondence, reports, orders, memorabilia, scrapbooks, commissions, financial records, and speeches organized in the following series: General Correspondence, Autograph Letters, Letterbooks, Field Dispatches and Telegrams, Military Papers, Subject File, Book and Speech File, Miscellany, Scrapbooks, and Oversize.
The papers relate chiefly to the Civil War, Reconstruction, Mexican border disputes, Indian wars, and military administration. There is very little material concerning Sheridan's family and personal life. Dominated by correspondence and reports, the papers document Sheridan's service as an army commander in the Civil War and his postwar commands up to and including that of commanding general of the United States Army. The papers also include material relating to George A. Forsyth's Europe-Asia observation tour; the Piegan expedition; Gouverneur K. Warren's court of inquiry; Rebecca Wright, a Federal spy at Winchester, Virginia; reconnaissance of Bighorn Mountain and the valleys of the Bighorn and Yellowstone rivers; and Henry Page's letterbooks as quartermaster for the Army of the Potomac. Correspondents include George A. Forsyth (aide and secretary), James W. Forsyth, Ulysses S. Grant, Michael V. Sheridan (his brother), and William T. Sherman. There are two letters from Abraham Lincoln to Sheridan, September 20 and October 22, 1864.
Included also is a draft of Sheridan's published memoirs. Following the destruction of some of Sheridan's papers in the Chicago fire of 1871, a large number of transcripts were made from the records of the War Department by his secretaries. These transcripts have been interfiled with the surviving original papers.
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in ten series:
General Correspondence, 1853-1888
Autograph Letters, 1865-1887
Letterbooks, 1871-1888
Field Dispatches and Telegrams, 1862-1883
Military Papers, 1853-1887
Subject File, 1863-1891
Book and Speech File, 1878-circa 1883
Miscellany, 1853-1896
Scrapbooks, 1861-1881
Oversize, 1853-1869
Container List
Available on microfilm. Shelf no. 19,308
- General Correspondence, 1853-1888 (Box 1-38, Reel 1-16)
  Letters, telegrams, and memoranda sent and received.
  Arranged chronologically with undated items at the end of most years and at the end of the series.
  - 1853, July (Box 1, Reel 1)
  - 1861, Apr.-Nov.
  - 1862
  - 1863, Feb.-Dec.
  - 1864
    - Jan.
    - Feb.
    - Mar.
    - Apr.
    - May
    - June
    - July
    - Aug.
    - Sept.
    - Oct.
    - Nov.
    - Dec.
    - Undated
  - 1865 (Box 2, Reel 1)
    - Jan.
    - Feb.
    - Mar.
    - May
    - Apr.
    - June 1-14
    - June 15-29
    - July 1-9
    - July 10-29
    - Aug. 1-11 (Box 3, Reel 1)
    - Aug. 14-28
    - Sept.
    - Oct. (Box 3, Reel 2)
    - Nov. 1-14
    - Dec. 1-18
    - Nov. 15-19
    - Dec. 19-31
  - 1866 (Box 4, Reel 2)
    - Jan. 2-13
    - Jan. 14-24
    - Jan. 26-30
    - Feb.
    - Mar.
    - Apr.
    - May
    - June
    - July
    - Aug. 1-15 (Box 5, Reel 2)
    - Aug. 17-30
    - Sept. 1-17
    - Sept. 18-30
    - Oct. 1-17
    - Oct. 18-31
    - Nov.
    - Dec.
  - 1867
    - Jan.
    - Feb.-Mar.
    - Apr.-May
    - June (Box 6, Reel 3)
    - July
    - Aug.
    - Sept.-Dec.
    - Undated
  - 1868
    - Jan.-Feb.
    - Apr.-Sept.
    - Oct.-Nov.
  - 1869
    - Jan.-Mar.
    - Apr.-July
    - Oct.-Dec.
  - 1870
    - Jan.-Apr.
    - June-Dec.
  - 1871
    - May-Aug.
    - Oct.
    - Nov. 2-13
    - Nov. 14-22
    - Nov. 24-30
    - Dec.
    - Undated
  - 1872 (Box 7, Reel 3)
    - Jan.-Feb.
    - Mar. 2-14
    - Mar. 15-31
    - Apr.
    - May
    - June 3-23
    - June 24-30 (Box 7, Reel 4)
    - July
    - Aug.
    - Sept.
    - Oct. 1-15 (Box 8, Reel 4)
    - Oct. 19-28
    - Nov.
    - Dec. 2-17
    - Dec. 18-31
    - Undated
      - 1 of 2
      - 2 of 2
  - 1873
    - Jan. 2-21
    - Jan. 22-27
    - Jan. 28-31
    - Feb.
    - Mar. 1-17 (Box 9, Reel 4)
    - Mar. 19-24
    - Mar. 25-31
    - Apr.
    - May
    - June 2-12 (Box 9, Reel 5)
    - June 13-30
    - July 1-21
    - July 22-30
    - Aug.
    - Sept. (Box 10, Reel 5)
    - Oct.
    - Nov. 3-18
    - Nov. 20-29
    - Dec.
    - Undated
  - 1874
    - Jan.
    - Feb.
    - Mar. 2-13
    - Mar. 14-31
    - Apr. (Box 11, Reel 5)
    - May
    - June
    - July 10-18
    - July 20-31 (Box 11, Reel 6)
    - Aug.
    - Sept. 1-10
    - Sept. 18-25
    - Oct.
    - Nov. 8-24
    - Nov. 27-30 (Box 12, Reel 6)
    - Dec. 1-17
    - Dec. 18-28
    - Undated
  - 1875
    - Jan. 2-5
    - Jan. 6-10
    - Jan. 11-15
    - Jan. 16-20
    - Jan. 21-31
    - Feb. 1-11 (Box 13, Reel 6)
    - Feb. 15-20
    - Feb. 20-28
    - Mar. 1-12
    - Mar. 12-28 (Box 13, Reel 7)
    - Apr.
    - May
    - June
    - July
    - Aug-Sept.
    - Oct.
    - Nov.
    - Dec. (Box 14, Reel 7)
    - Undated
  - 1876
    - Jan.
    - Feb. 2-26
    - Feb. 28-29
    - Mar. 1-17
    - Mar. 21-30
    - Apr. 3-21
    - Apr. 24-29
    - May 2-5
    - May 13-20 (Box 15, Reel 7)
    - May 24-31
    - June
    - July
    - Aug. 4-17
    - Aug. 18-22
    - Aug. 23-31
    - Sept. (Box 15, Reel 8)
    - Oct. (Box 16, Reel 8)
    - Nov.
    - Dec.
    - Undated
      - 1 of 4
      - 2 of 4
      - 3 of 4
      - 4 of 4
  - 1877
    - Jan. 4-26
    - Jan. 27-31
    - Feb.
    - Mar. 12-19 (Box 17, Reel 8)
    - Mar. 20-30
    - Apr.
    - May
    - June 1-9
    - June 12-23
    - July 14-25
    - July 26-30
    - Aug.
    - Sept.
    - Oct. (Box 18, Reel 8)
    - Nov. 1-21
    - Nov. 23-30
    - Dec. 1-16
    - Dec. 17-29
    - Undated (Box 18, Reel 9)
      - 1 of 6
      - 2 of 6
      - 3 of 6
      - 4 of 6
      - 5 of 6
      - 6 of 6
  - 1878 (Box 19, Reel 9)
    - Jan. 2-15
    - Jan. 16-28
    - Feb.
    - Mar.
    - Apr.
    - May 2-11
    - May 17-31
    - June
    - July 1-5
    - July 5-27
    - Aug.
    - Sept. 2-12 (Box 20, Reel 9)
    - Sept. 14-28
    - Oct. 2-8
    - Oct. 9-31
    - Nov. 2-9
    - Nov. 11-19 (Box 20, Reel 10)
    - Nov. 22-29
    - Dec. 2-19
    - Dec. 20-31
    - Undated
      - 1 of 3
      - 2 of 3
      - 3 of 3
  - 1879 (Box 21, Reel 10)
    - Jan. 2-11
    - Jan. 13-31
    - Feb. 1-7
    - Feb. 8-13
    - Feb. 14-19
    - Feb. 20-25
    - Feb. 26-28
    - Mar. 1-21 (Box 22, Reel 10)
    - Mar. 22-26
    - Mar. 27-31
    - Apr. 1-9
    - Apr. 10-15
    - Apr. 20-24
    - May 1-7 (Box 23, Reel 10)
    - May 8-10
    - May 11-13
    - May 14-24
    - June
    - July 2-9 (Box 23, Reel 11)
    - July 10-15
    - July 16-21 (Box 24, Reel 11)
    - July 22-24
    - July 25-29
    - Aug. 1-9
    - Aug. 11-19
    - Aug. 20-31
    - Sept. (Box 25, Reel 11)
    - Oct.
    - Nov.
    - Dec.
    - Undated
      - 1 of 7
      - 2 of 7
      - 3 of 7
      - 4 of 7
      - 5 of 7
      - 6 of 7
      - 7 of 7
  - 1880 (Box 26, Reel 11)
    - Mar.
    - Apr.
    - May 1-19
    - May 20-24
    - May 26-31
    - June
    - July
    - Aug. (Box 26, Reel 12)
    - Sept. 11-20 (Box 27, Reel 12)
    - Sept. 21-30
    - Oct.
    - Nov.
    - Dec. 2-14
    - Dec. 15-30
    - Undated
  - 1881 (Box 28, Reel 12)
    - Jan.
    - Feb. 5-10
    - Feb. 14-22
    - Mar. 10-19
    - Mar. 21-28
    - Apr.
    - May
    - June
    - July 1-8
    - July 9-15
    - Sept. 5-15 (Box 29, Reel 12)
    - Sept. 16-20
    - Sept. 21-30
    - Oct. 1-15
    - Oct. 18-19
    - Oct. 21-29
    - Nov. 2-10
    - Nov. 11-16 (Box 30, Reel 12)
    - Nov. 17-21
    - Nov. 22-30 (Box 30, Reel 13)
    - Dec. 1-7
    - Dec. 8-12
    - Dec. 17-31
    - Undated
  - 1882 (Box 31, Reel 13)
    - Jan. 3-13
    - Jan. 14-21
    - Feb.
    - Mar. 3-10
    - Mar. 13-31
    - Apr. 1-8
    - Apr. 11-21
    - Apr. 23-29
    - May 4-20 (Box 32, Reel 13)
    - May 22-27
    - June 1-10
    - June 12-23
    - June 24-28
    - July 3-12
    - July 13-20
    - July 24-31
    - Aug. (Box 33, Reel 13)
    - Sept. 4-7
    - Sept. 8-15
    - Sept. 16-30 (Box 33, Reel 14)
    - Oct. 2-23
    - Oct. 29-31
    - Nov. 1-10
    - Nov. 14-22
    - Dec.
    - Undated
  - 1883 (Box 34, Reel 14)
    - Jan.
    - Feb.
    - Mar.
    - Apr.-May
    - June-July
    - Aug.
    - Sept.
    - Oct.
    - Nov.
    - Dec.
    - Undated
  - 1884
    - Jan.
    - Feb.
    - Mar.
    - Apr.
    - May
    - June (Box 35, Reel 14)
    - July
    - Aug.
    - Sept.
    - Oct.
    - Nov.
    - Dec.
    - Undated
  - 1885 (Box 35, Reel 15)
    - Jan.
    - Feb.
    - Mar.
    - Apr.
    - May
    - June
    - July
    - Aug.
    - Sept. (Box 36, Reel 15)
    - Oct.
    - Nov.
    - Dec.
    - Undated
  - 1886
    - Jan.
    - Feb.
    - Mar.
    - Apr.
    - May
    - June
    - July
    - Aug.
    - Oct.-Nov.
    - Dec.
    - Undated
  - 1887
    - Jan.-Feb.
    - Mar.-Apr.
    - May-June
    - July-Sept
    - Oct.-Dec.
    - Undated
  - 1888 (Box 37, Reel 15)
    - Jan.
    - Feb.
    - Mar.
    - Apr.
    - May
    - June
    - Undated
  - 1870s (Box 37, Reel 16)
    - Undated
      - 1 of 3
      - 2 of 3
      - 3 of 3
  - 1880s (Box 38, Reel 16)
    - Undated
      - 1 of 4
      - 2 of 4
      - 3 of 4
      - 4 of 4
  - 1800s
    - Undated
      - 1 of 5
      - 2 of 5
      - 3 of 5
      - 4 of 5
      - 5 of 5
- Autograph Letters, 1865-1887 (Box 39, Reel 17)
  Letters received from William T. Sherman and Ulysses S. Grant and miscellaneous letters sent by Sheridan.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person and thereunder chronologically.
  - Grant, Ulysses S., to Sheridan, 1865-1881 (Box 39, Reel 17)
  - Sheridan to others, 1865-1885
  - Sherman, William T., to Sheridan
    - 1868-1877
    - 1878-1887
- Letterbooks, 1871-1888 (Box 40-49, Reel 18-42)
  Copies of letters sent and received.
  Grouped into general correspondence and correspondence signed by aides and clerks and arranged thereunder chronologically. Most volumes are indexed.
  - General correspondence (Box 40, Reel 18)
    - 1871, Oct. 12-1872, May 6
    - 1871, Oct. 21-1872, Dec. 31 (includes correspondence dated 1874 and 1876) (Box 40, Reel 19)
    - 1873, Jan. 22-1875, Dec. 12 (Box 41, Reel 20)
    - 1874, Dec. 10-1875, Dec. 31 (Box 41, Reel 22)
    - 1876, Jan. 3-1878, Dec. 24 (includes correspondence dated 1879) (Box 41, Reel 21)
    - 1879, Jan. 4-1881, Apr. 29 (Box 42, Reel 23)
    - 1881, May 7-1883, July 20 (Box 42, Reel 24)
    - 1883, July 20- Oct. 23 (Box 42, Reel 25)
    - 1883, Nov. 1-1885, Sept. 8 (Box 43, Reel 26)
    - 1885, Sept. 28-1887, Apr. 11 (Box 44, Reel 27)
    - 1887, Apr. 13-1888, May 4 (Box 44, Reel 28)
  - Correspondence signed by aides and clerks (Box 45, Reel 29)
    - 1871, Oct. 23-1873, Sept. 20
    - 1873, Sept. 22-1875, June 11 (Box 45, Reel 30)
    - 1875, June 22-1877, Mar. 5 (Box 45, Reel 31)
    - 1875, June 15-1879, Sept. 20 (Box 46, Reel 32)
    - 1879, Oct. 3-1881, July 5 (Box 46, Reel 33)
    - 1871, Oct. 23-1876, Dec. 27 (Box 46, Reel 34)
    - 1881, Sept. 15-1884, Oct. 25 (Box 47, Reel 35)
    - 1877, Jan. 5-1881, Sept. 20; 1884, Mar. 28 (Box 47, Reel 36)
    - 1883, Nov. 2-1885, Mar. 30 (Box 48, Reel 37)
    - 1885, Mar. 30-1885, Dec. 30 (Box 48, Reel 38)
    - 1883, Nov. 9-1887, June 2 (Box 48, Reel 39)
    - 1886, Jan. 2-1886, Dec. 29 (Box 49, Reel 40)
    - 1886, Jan. 2-1888, Sept. 5 (Box 49, Reel 41)
    - 1887, Jan. 3-1888, Aug. 14 (Box 49, Reel 42)
- Field Dispatches and Telegrams, 1862-1883 (Box 50-59, Reel 43-64)
  Field dispatches and telegrams sent and received.
  Grouped as items sent and items received and filed thereunder chronologically. Some volumes are indexed.
  - Sent, 1862, June-1871, Oct. (incomplete film ends at 1865, Mar. 25) (Box 50, Reel 43)
  - Received (Box 50, Reel 44)
    - 1862, May-1865, Mar.
    - 1865, Mar.-1871, July (Box 50, Reel 45)
  - Sent (Box 51, Reel 46)
    - Vol. 1, 1862, June-1864, Sept.
    - Vol. 2, 1864, Sept.-1867, June (Box 52, Reel 47)
    - Vol. 3, 1867, June-1871, Oct. (Box 53, Reel 48)
  - Received (Box 54, Reel 49)
    - Vol. 1, 1862, May-1864, June
    - Vol. 2, 1864, June-1871, July (Box 55, Reel 50)
  - Sent (Box 56, Reel 51)
    - 1872, July-Nov.
    - 1872, Nov.-1873, Mar.
    - 1873, Mar.-June
    - 1873, July-Dec.
    - 1874
      - Jan.-June
      - June-Aug.
      - Sept.-Nov. (Box 56, Reel 52)
      - Nov.-Dec.
    - 1875, Jan.-July
    - 1875, July-1876, Jan.
    - 1876 (Box 57, Reel 54)
      - Jan.-May
      - May-July
      - July-Aug.
      - Aug.-Sept. (Box 57, Reel 53)
    - 1876, Sept. 18-1877, Feb. 5
    - 1877
      - Feb.-May
      - May-Aug.
      - Aug.-Oct. (Box 57, Reel 55)
      - Oct.
    - 1873, Jan.-1875, Apr. (Box 58, Reel 57)
    - 1875, Apr.- 1875, Dec. (Box 58, Reel 60)
    - 1876, Jan.-1877, Mar. (Box 58A, Reel 58)
    - 1877, Mar.-1877, Sept. (Box 58A, Reel 59)
    - 1877, Aug.-1879, Mar. (Box 58B, Reel 56)
    - 1879, Mar.-1879, July (Box 58B, Reel 61)
    - 1879, July-1881, Apr. (Box 59, Reel 62)
    - 1881, May-1883, Oct. (Box 59, Reel 63)
    - (blank pages 744-998) (Box 59, Reel 64)
- Military Papers, 1853-1887 (Box 60-89, Reel 65-87)
  Endorsements, official correspondence of the Department of the Gulf, operations reports, orders, and reports.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and filed thereunder by topic or chronology.
  - Endorsements (Box 60, Reel 65)
    - 1872, May 1-Dec. 31 (index only)
    - 1873, Jan. 2-1877, Dec. 16 (incomplete film ends at 1876, Sept. 7) (Box 60A, Reel 66)
    - 1877, Nov. 27-1879, Dec. 18 (Box 60B, Reel 67)
    - 1880, Mar. 30-1883, May 28 (Box 61, Reel 68)
    - 1883, June 2-Oct. 23 (Box 61, Reel 69)
    - 1883, Nov. 2-1886, July 31 (Box 62, Reel 70)
    - 1886, Aug. 4-1887, Apr. 14 (Box 63, Reel 70)
  - Official correspondence, Department of the Gulf (Box 64, Reel 71)
    - 1866-1869, vol. 2
    - 1865-1868, fragments of another volume
  - Operations reports (Box 65, Reel 72)
    - Copies
      - Vol. 1
        - Various reports
        - Division and brigade commanders' reports, Cavalry Corps, Army of the Potomac, 1864
          - Pages 1-101
      - Vol. 2 (Box 66, Reel 73)
        - Division and brigade commanders' reports, Cavalry Corps, Army of the Potomac, 1864
          - Pages 102-491 (Box 67, Reel 73)
      - Vol. 3 (Box 67, Reel 73)
        - Shenandoah Valley campaign
      - Vol. 4 (Box 68, Reel 74)
        - Shenandoah Valley campaign
      - Vol. 5 (Box 69, Reel 74)
        - Shenandoah Valley campaign
      - Vol. 6 (Box 70, Reel 75)
        - Various reports
      - Vol. 7 (Box 71, Reel 75)
        - Various reports
      - Vol. 8 (Box 72, Reel 76)
        - Military Division of the Missouri (1868-1869)
      - Vol. 9 (Box 73, Reel 76)
        - Military Division of the Missouri (1869)
    - Letterpress copies (Box 74, Reel 77)
      - Vol. 1
        - Various reports, pages 1-335
        - Division and brigade commanders' reports, Cavalry Corps, Army of the Potomac, 1864
          - Pages 336-759
          - Pages 761-834 (Box 74, Reel 78)
        - Shenandoah Valley campaign, 1864-1865, pages 835-996
      - Vol. 2, Shenandoah Valley campaign, 1864-1865
        - Pages 1-533
        - Pages 534-999 (Box 74, Reel 79)
      - Vol. 3 (Box 75, Reel 79)
        - Shenandoah Valley campaign, 1864-1865; Winchester, Va., raid, 1865, pages 1-164
        - Appomattox campaign, 1864-1865
          - Pages 165-333
          - Pages 334-449 (Box 75, Reel 80)
        - Various reports, 1864-1869, pages 450-993
      - Vol. 4 (Box 76, Reel 81)
        - Sub-reports of engagements, campaigns, and scouts against Indians, Military Division of Missouri, 1869, pages 1-335
        - Sub-reports of military operations against the Indians and miscellaneous papers pertaining to Indian matters, 1868-1869
          - Pages 336-797
          - Pages 798-997 (Box 76, Reel 82)
      - Operations reports index to vols. 1-5 (lacking vol. 5)
  - Orders (Box 77, Reel 82)
    - 1853-1864
    - 1853-1867 (Box 78, Reel 83)
    - 1864-1875 (Box 78, Reel 84)
    - 1855 (Box 79, Reel 84)
    - 1856
    - 1857
    - 1861
    - 1862
    - 1863
    - 1864
      - Jan.-Mar.
      - Apr. 1-14
      - Apr. 15-30
      - May
      - June
      - July 1-14
      - July 15-31
      - Aug.
      - Sept.
      - Oct.
      - Nov.
      - Dec.
    - 1865 (Box 80, Reel 84)
      - Jan.-Feb.
      - Mar.-Apr.
      - May
      - June-Sept.
      - Oct.-Dec.
    - 1866 (Box 80, Reel 85)
    - 1867
    - 1868
    - 1869
    - 1870
    - 1871
    - 1872
    - 1873
    - 1874
    - 1875
    - 1876
    - 1877
    - 1878
    - 1882
    - 1884
    - Undated
    - Miscellaneous
  - Reports (Box 81, Reel 85)
    - 1862
    - 1863
    - 1864
      - 1 of 3
      - 2 of 3
      - 3 of 3
    - 1864-1865
      - 1 of 2
      - 2 of 2
    - 1865 (Box 82, Reel 85)
      - 1 of 3
      - 2 of 3
      - 3 of 3
    - 1865-1866
    - 1866
    - 1867
    - 1868 (Box 83, Reel 86)
    - 1869
    - 1870
    - 1871
    - 1872
    - 1873 (Box 84, Reel 86)
      - 1 of 4
      - 2 of 4
      - 3 of 4
      - 4 of 4
    - 1874 (Box 85, Reel 86)
      - 1 of 2
      - 2 of 2
    - 1875
      - 1 of 3
      - 2 of 3
      - 3 of 3 [1874-1878]
    - 1876 (Box 86, Reel 86)
      - 1 of 6
      - 2 of 6
      - 3 of 6
      - 4 of 6
      - 5 of 6
      - 6 of 6
    - 1877 (Box 87, Reel 86)
    - 1878
      - 1 of 4
      - 2 of 4
      - 3 of 4
      - 4 of 4 (Box 87, Reel 87)
    - 1879
    - 1880 (Box 88, Reel 87)
      - 1 of 2
      - 2 of 2
    - 1881
    - 1882
    - 1883
    - 1885
    - 1886 (Box 89, Reel 87)
    - Undated
      - 1 of 4
      - 2 of 4
      - 3 of 4
      - 4 of 4
- Subject File, 1863-1891 (Box 90-95, Reel 87-94)
  Correspondence, telegram books, reports, newspaper clippings, and printed matter.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject and thereunder chronologically.
  - Forsyth, George A., Europe-Asia observation tour (Box 90, Reel 87)
    - 1876
    - 1875
    - 1877
    - 1876
    - 1875-1876